Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Civil War and Post-War Period, 1860-1868
  - The Great November Contest. Patriotism versus Bummerism. [Presidential election, Reonstruction], 1868 (Folder FF-95, Item 1868-25)
    Lithograph: Entered...1868 by Bromley & Co...
  - Old Soldiers' Advocate -- Extra: Leading, Following, Rebelling [Reconstruction, Benjamin Wade], circa 1868 (Folder FF-146, Item [1868]-No #)
    Published by G.F. Lewis, Cleveland, Ohio.
- Series VI. Late 19th Century, 1869-1899
  The series includes prints dating from 1869 to 1899, that is, from the beginning of U.S. President Ulysses S. Grant's administration to the close of the 19th century. There are about 530 prints in the series. About 270 of these, or about half the series, concern the Spanish-American War, with images from Puck, The Judge, The Bee, The Verdict, and other publications by Eugene Zimmerman, Victor Gillam, Grant E. Hamilton, Louis Dalrymple, Joseph Keppler, J.S. Pughe, Rose O'Neill Latham, Samuel Ehrhart, Horace Taylor, George Luks, MIRS, E. Noble, and others.
  The series also includes many prints from the "Darktown" series of the 1880s drawn by Thomas Worth, James Cameron, and others and published by Currier & Ives. These prints presented racist images of African-Americans in various before-and-after scenes; "before" scenes included African-Americans engaging in some social, leisure or other such activity, with the resulting "after" scene one of ineptitude and mayhem.
  As with the earlier series, presidential elections are represented here, especially that of 1872. The 1872 election prints include Ulysses Grant as a do-nothing president surrounded by corruption against Horace Greeley as naïve, inexperienced and a front for the return of the Confederacy. Some of these 1872 election prints include appeals to African-Americans to switch their allegiance from the Republican Party. The elections of 1876 (Hayes/Tilden), 1880 (Garfield/Hancock), 1884 (Cleveland/Blaine), 1888 and 1892 (Cleveland/Harrison), and 1896 (McKinley/Bryan) are all represented to at least some degree. The politician and former Civil War general Benjamin F. Butler makes many appearances in the prints.
  Financial themes run throughout the series, including images of railroad barons, financial dealings (gold panic of '69), taxation, the economic power of monopolists/industrialists, and tariff reform in the 1880s-90s. Political corruption, especially in the form of Tammany, is a common theme. Social caricatures are also found in the series, including images of women asserting rights/new roles at expense of men/masculinity and sets of "men on the street" caricatures of well-known political, religious, business and other figures.
  Caricaturists not mentioned above but represented in the series include Thomas Nast, Frank Bellew, Vincent Brooks, Day & Son, D.E. Cronin, and others.
  - The Statue Unveiled. Or the Colossus of Roads. [Cornelius Vanderbilt, railroads], 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-1)
  - The Last Ditch. [Presidential election], 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-2)
    Pen drawing: Anonymous. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 30, 1923.
  - The Horse for the Money! Dexter in Danger. (handwritten), 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-3)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron. This is proof of 1869-4. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 22, 1903.
  - The Horse for the Money. Dexter in Danger., 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-4)
    Lithograph: Signed by J. Cameron; Published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec. 17, 1903.
  - The Age of Iron. Man as He Expects to Be. [Feminist Movement], 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-5)
  - The Boss of the Ring. [James Fisk], 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-6)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 17, 1901. Pencil drawing on back: "Be not wise ..."
  - Above: Preface. Vo-M-55. Below: "Mr. President-Elect, Ulysses S. Grant,...", 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-7)
    Woodcut from an illustrated newspaper dated January 2, 1869.
  - The "Boy of the Period" Stirring up the Animals. Black Friday. [James Fisk and Gold Panic of September 24, 1869] (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-8)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. There is a smaller facsimile copy as well.
  - The Age of Brass. Or the Triumphs of Women's Rights. [Feminist Movement], 1869 (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-9)
  - Above: Not "Love" but Justice. [Two cartoons] from London Punch May 29, 1869; Harper's Weekly, June 26, 1869. below: Sir Jonathan Falstaff [dialogue folllows] Sir John Bull Falstaff [dialogue follows]. [Alabama Claims] (Folder FF-96, Item 1869-10)
    Wood engraving: Thomas Nast. Acquisition(?) date on back: Apr. 16, 1906.
  - Selling Out Cheap! [Charles Sumner], 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-1)
  - Series of 9 wood engravings (mainly by F. Bellew and H.L. Stephens) reprinted from periodicals dealing with the election in New York State [support for Democratic gubernatorial candidate John T. Hoffman]., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-2 to 1870-10)
    Nine Wood Engravings: The Young Democ Trying to Put the Big Sachem's [Tammany] Pipe Out; The Prize Calf "S.L. Woodford," Fattened by Messrs. Greeley and Curtis for the Special Purpose of Being Cut Up on Tuesday, November 8th.; Mr. Greeley. "Pray Take a Seat, Mr. Woodford; I Wouldn't on any Account Deprive You,"...; The New Pandora's Box. [Chinese as cheap labor in competition with tradesmen]; Our Efficient Navy Department. [sinking of the Oneida]; Barnacles on Our Commerce. [taxes]; Alas! Poor Cuba! [Grant's refusal to recognize Cuba]; A Sight Too Bad! [Grant's refusal to recognize Cuba]; Comforting Assurances. [Republican gubernatorial candidate Woodford]. Mainly by F. Bellew and H.L. Stephens.
  - Liederkranz Illustrated. The Festivities at Their Height. [Sketches taken at the New York Academy of Music, Thursday Evening, February 24, 1870.] (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-11)
    Lithographs: Issued by Ferd. Mayer & Sons, Lithographers. Sketches taken by their special artist, Norman J. Mayer.
  - Americus Club Ball, 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-12)
    Photograph: Photograph (Wurts Bros. Photo. NYC.) of a drawing. Handwritten on back: "This drawing made during Tweed's regime and was found in cellar of Old Academy of Music. 14th St. & Irving Place."; "Purchased from Wurts Bros., Jan. 17, 1933"; "Tweed's arrest was ordered by the Supreme Court in 1871. Convicted 1872. Died 1875."
  - Health to the King and Bismark!! Heif dem Koenig und Bismark!!, 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-13)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron; published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Great Race for the Western Stakes 1870. [Railroads] (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-14)
  - New Map of Europe, For 1870. Title on face of map: Europe From a French Design. (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-15)
    Colored lithograph: Published by J.C. Thompson. Below map, individual countries are described in form of human and animal figures. Acquisition(?) date on back: Feb. 14, 1950.
  - The Bottom Out. Every Thing Coming Down. [Gold Speculation], 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-16)
    2 copies. Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Copy 1: Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 22, 1903. Copy 2 (cropped): Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 20, 1928.
  - Napoleon's Strategy, Or King William Out-Generaled., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-17)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"; Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - Above: The Sweet Bye and Bye or What Tweed Knows about It. Below: [Five verses parodying the popular hymn.], 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-18)
    Wood engraving: Novelty Ballad Depot. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 30, 1904.
  - The Latest Sensation! The Beecher Minstrels., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-19)
    Wood engraving: Signed J. Keppler, published by M.J. Ivers. Acquisition(?) date on front: July 30, 1907.
  - Above: La gloire militaire en Amerique. [Two pictures one above the other] Avant. Assassinat des Indiens Piegans. Below: Apres. a continuar, selon les Batailles aussi glorifies., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-20)
    Pen lithograph: Signed J.R., Paris 1870.
  - Benjamin F. Butler items, 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-22)
    This is a combination of items: A letter dated May 20, 1870 from Benjamin Butler (addressee removed); a newspaper's reproduction of woodcut "'Old Cockeye' on the warpath" by Bellew; an engraving of Butler by G.E. Perine; and an engraving? of a crying Butler.
  - The "Gallic Rooster" at the Front on the banks of the Rhine., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-23)
    Lithograph: Signed Avery des. Entered...1870 by C. Currier & Co....
  - "A Live Jackass Kicking a Dead Lion." And Such a Lion! And Such a Jackass! [Origin of Donkey symbol], 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-24)
    Woodcut: Harper's Weekly, Jan. 15, 1870 from pen and ink drawing by Thomas Nast. Missing; not in folder on Jan. 24, 2022.
  - Above: New Tammany taxing, and taking and tying, The city degraded, in slavery lying, While few by vain means for their freedom are trying. Below: They nominate themselves, and persuade the people that it is to their interest to elect them; ..., 1870 (Folder FF-97, Item 1870-25)
    Engraving: Anonymous. Illustration for 3 page text (political campaign material, included). Acquisition(?) date on back: Sept. 22, 1944.
  - The Jack Knife War. [Tweed], 1871 (Folder FF-97, Item 1871-1)
  - [No Title] Title on published woodcut: "The Tammany Tiger (or) The Tammany Tiger Loose.", 1871 (Folder FF-97, Item 1871-2)
    Proof from Woodcut: By Thomas Nast. Note in pencil on back. "Reproduction of a Caricature by Thomas Nast Drawn and engraved on wood published in "Harper's Weekly" Nov. 11, 1871. (The first use of the famous Tiger (Tammany Symbol) Presented by Mrs. Thomas Nast Sept. 26, 1906.
  - Coppy's Lie Down. [Orangemen's Parade], 1871 (Folder FF-97, Item 1871-3)
    Wood engraving: No imprint. In pencil on front: "'Orange' Riot - July 1871"
  - Returning to Head-Quarters. [Presidential election, Grant], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-1)
  - The End of Long Branch. [Presidential election, Greeley, Grant], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-2)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron. Published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"; Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Elephant and His Keepers. [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-3)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"; Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The New "Confederate Cruiser." [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-4)
    2 copies. Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published Currier & Ives. Copy 1: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"; Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - [No Title] "Horace Greeley and the Salary Grab Bill" (in pencil below), 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-5)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Oct. 3, 1903.
  - Men on the Avenue. No. 10. Fifth Avenue Journal Series. [August Belmont], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-6)
    Wood engraving: Signed Bellew, [published by] R. Shugg & Co. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan. 13, 1907.
  - A "Dodge" That Won't Work. [Presidential election, Greeley attempt to appeal for African-American votes], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-7)
  - The New Fountain of Democracy, [on one copy: "Swill Milk for Hungry Suckers."] [Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-8)
    3 copies. Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Copy 1: Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906. Copy 2: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. [Copy 3]: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Acquisition(?) date on back: Dec. 1, 1952.
  - Columbia.- Well, Mrs. Greeley, how have you been getting along since your con--, ahem, since the birth of your children? Mrs. Greeley.- Pretty well, I thank you,--but the children don't seem to get along,--their milk don't agree with them., 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-9)
    Lithograph: Pulished by Kellogg & Bulkeley Co. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 16, 1904.
  - The Senatorial Turkey Gobbler. Men of the Day. No. 5. Fifth Avenue Journal Series. [Roscoe Conkling], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-10)
    Colored lithograph: Signed Bellew. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan. 13, 1927.
  - The "Last Ditch" of the Democratic Party. [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-11)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives.
  - Splitting the Party. The Entering Wedge. [Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-12)
    2 copies. Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Copy 1: Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906. Copy 2: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"; Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946. Also in pencil on back: "5/9/1908"
  - Red Hot Republicans on the Democratic Gridiron. "The San Domingo War Dance." [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-13)
  - A Nice Family Party. [Grant, political corruption], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-14)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Stamped twice on back: "Collections of The New-York Historical Society". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - A Philosopher in Ecstasy. "By George! I've got it!!" [Nomination of Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-98, Item 1872-15)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 12, 1906.
  - The Military Ring. [Grant], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-16)
    2 copies. Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Copy 1: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Copy 2: Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Philosopher's Stone. [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-17)
    Lithograph: Signed Donaghy, Del., published by American News Co., agents for Supplying the Trade. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting". Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 7, 1946.
  - The Political Belisarius. From the original painting by C.G. Rosenberg, painted to the order of and owned by A. Oakey Hall, Esq. [Presidential election, Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-18)
    Photograph: Photo by Gurney.
  - Political Ladder. [advocacy of an anti-corruption candidate oath], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-20)
    Wood engraving: Signed Smart sc. Entered...1872, by Thomas A. Davies... Acquisition(?) date on front: July 1901.
  - Above: War! War! War! to the knife on Political Corruption. [Followed by text]. Below: Political Smash-Up., 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-21)
    Wood engraving: Signed Smart sc. Entered...1872, by Thomas A. Davies... Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 21, 1905.
  - "A Popular Verdict." [Presidential election, Greeley, Grant], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-22)
    Lithograph: Signed F.J. Brittain del., published by Taylor & Co. Publishers.
  - Above left: Americans behold the change! ... Above right: Americans behold our freedom! ... Below left: Things as they should be: Sovereigns directing their servants. Below right: Things as they are: Servants leading Sovereigns with rings in their noses. [Reform, Political corruption], 1872 (Folder FF-146, Item 1872-23)
    Wood engraving: Entered...1872 by Thomas A. Davies...
  - Thereby Hangs a Tail - The Virtuous monkey up a tree. Fifth Avenue Journal Series. [Charles O'Connor], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-24)
    Wood engraving: By Augustus P. Dunlop.
  - The Chappaqua Farmer. [Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-25)
    Lithograph: By D. Chalmers, after painting by Samuel J. Chapman, 1872. Stamped on front: 2nd Copy delivered to The Art Gallery, Nov. 22 1897. In pencil on back: "Gift of Jacques Schurre, March 1987.
  - Statesmen. No. 118. [Greeley], 1872 (Folder FF-99, Item 1872-26)
    Print: Vanity Fair. No. 194.
  - The Fifth Avenue Journal Series: Men on the Avenue., 1872 (Folder FF-100, Item 1872-no #)
    Wood engravings. No. 1 [James Gordon Bennett, Jr.] by Grant-Co. sc.; No. 2 [Judge Gunning Bedford]; No. 3 [Joe Howard] by Grant-Co. sc.; No. 4 [James Lewis] by Grant-Co. sc; No. 8 [Chas. S. Spencer] by Bellew, published by R. Shugg & Co., entered... by Augustus P. Dunlop; No. 9 [Henry Stebbins] by Bellew, published by R. Shugg & Co., entered... by Augustus P. Dunlop; No. 10 [August Belmont] by Bellew, published by R. Shugg & Co., entered... by Augustus P. Dunlop.
  - The Fifth Avenue Journal Series: Men of the Day., 1872 (Folder FF-101, Item 1872-no #)
    Colored lithographs.
    No. 2 [H.W. Beecher] Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 3 [M.M. (Brick) Pomeroy] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 4, B. Gratz Brown, by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 5, The Senatorial Turley Gobbler [Roscoe Conkling], by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 6 [Whitelaw Reid] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 7, A Cabinet Ornament. One of the Upper Crust-acea [Hamilton Fish] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 8 [W.F.G. Shanks] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 10, A Sweet Thing in Reform. Men of the Day (After To-Morrow) [George W. Custis] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 11 [Augustus Schell] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 12 [Max Maretzek] by CL, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872
    No. 13 [Robert Bonner] Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 15 [Francis Kiernan] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
    No. 17 [Dr. Chapin] by Bellew, Entered...Augustus P. Dunlop...1872, R. Shugg-Co.
  - Above: Time is Money; Below: A Prized Trotter [Four lines of verse follow], 1873 (Folder FF-102, Item 1873-1)
    Lithograph: Signed J. Cameron, Del., published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec. 17, 1903.
  - The Siege of Plymouth A.D. 1874. A Protestant, Didit. [Henry Ward Beecher/Tilton affair] (Folder FF-103, Item 1874-1)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec. 21, 1907.
  - Vindication! [9 lines of verse follow.] [Henry Ward Beecher/Tilton affair], 1874 (Folder FF-103, Item 1874-2)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Sept. 17, 1897.
  - No Slate Here. [Refusal of a third presidential term for Grant], 1874 (Folder FF-103, Item 1874-3)
  - The Third-Term Panic. [Origin of Elephant Symbol], 1874 (Folder FF-103, Item 1874-4)
    Woodcut: Harper's Weekly from pen and ink drawing by Thomas Nast, Nov. 7, 1874. Missing from folder, Jan. 24, 2022.
  - Independent Democrats Vote Against Arbitrary and Aristocratic Kelly Ring! [John Kelly, Mayor Wickham], 1875 (Folder FF-104, Item 1875-1)
    Wood engraving: [signed] J.F.S.
  - An Interesting Widow, Bereaved But Not Inconsolable. "You see I have no hesitation in speaking about it. I am not like a young maiden; I am more like a widow. I know what I want and I am not afraid to ask for it.." Benjamin F. Butler's speech at Lawrence, Mass., August 21., 1875 (Folder FF-104, Item 1875-2a)
    2 copies. Lithograph: Drawn by Thomas Nast, The Graphic Co. Lith. Copy 1: Acquisition(?) date on back: July 15, 1958 (Norman).
  - "Widow Butler" [Benjamin F. Butler], 1875 (Folder FF-104, Item 1875-2b)
    Reproduction of pen and ink drawing by Thomas Nast entitled, "Widow Butler", a caricature of Ben. F. Butler. [Based on speech by Butler at Lawrence, Mass. Aug. 21, 1875.]
  - Beware! [Importance of excluding Catholicism from public schools], 1875 (Folder FF-104, Item 1875-no #)
    Woodcut: Harper's Weekly from pen and ink drawing by Thomas Nast, July 3, 1875.
  - -- Bunker Hill Centennial Memento --, 1875 (Folder FF-104, Item 1975-no #)
    Lithograph: Signed F.T. Vance, published by Vance, Parsloe & Co., Publishers & Lith.
  - Up in a Balloon. [Presidential election, Tilden & Hendricks], 1876 (Folder FF-105, Item 1876-1)
    Lithograph: Published by Currier & Ives. Acquisition(?) date on back: March 20, 1946.
  - The Opening of the 7th Seal of Radicalism. California Anno Domini 1876, or Sooner.(American institutions and society overcome by Asians and African-Americans] (Folder FF-105, Item 1876-2)
    Lithograph: Signed R.S., no imprint. Acquisition(?) date on back: April 16, 1914.
  - The Ingenious Mother. These were the pants of your papa. [Set to the music by J. Offenbach with a musical score.], 1876 (Folder FF-105, Item 1876-3)
    Lithograph: Signed D.C.F., copyright 1876 by D.C. Fabronius. Acquisition(?) date on back: Dec. 6, 1950.
  - Why Bless My Heart, Johnny, You're Welcome! How's Your Mother? [Uncle Sam & Centennial '76], 1876 (Folder FF-105, Item 1876-4)
    Photograph of a lithograph: Copyrighted and published by J.E. Ryder. Acquisition(?) date on back: Sept. 15, 1951.
  - Puck's Contributors. Puck und Seine Mitarbeiter. [Puck overseeing politicians, crooks, and other "contributors" to its satire], 1876 (Folder FF-105, Item 1876-5)
    Lithograph: Drawn by J. Keppler, published by Mayer, Merkel & Ottomann. On reverse side are advertisements and "Prospectus." [In German].
  - Above: Brigham Young's Successors'. -- New Rule. Below: "Last into Bed Put Out the Light" old proverb. [Mormon polygamy], 1877 (Folder FF-106, Item 1877-1)
    Lithograph: Published by S. Marks & Sons. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 23, 1906.
  - Above: "The New Prophet, Brigham Young's Successor." Below: "He can't forget the days when he was young." Comic song. [Mormon polygamy], 1877 (Folder FF-106, Item 1877-2)
    Lithograph: No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on front: Apr. 23, 1906.
  - Top picture: Service of a Writ of Replevin by Worchester County Deputy Sheriff, July 17, 1877, on a defenseless and unprotected lady... Bottom picture: High Sheriff Sprague's style of treatment of litigants who request him to perform a sworn official duty. (Folder FF-106, Item 1877-3)
    Reproduction of pen and ink drawing by S.L.D.: By The Photo-electrotype Co., Boston.
  - The Bill Poster's Dream. (New Series.), 1877 (Folder FF-106, Item 1877-4)
    Lithograph: Signed Emil Speiner (?), published by Ferd. Mayer, Genl. Liths. Entered.. by the Novelty Publishing Co.
  - The Major and the Judge, 1877 (Folder FF-106, Item 1877-5)
    Colored lithograph: Copyrighted by G.F. Gilman, 1877. on the back in pencil: "Harrington & Hart."; "Return to Mr. Child -"
  - Above: Old Fable Modernized. Below: Officious Fly -- JHW -- I trust that my weight does not embarass you? Ruminating Ox -- BFB -- Not in the least I assure you. Had you not spoken I should not have known you were there. [Benjamin F. Butler], 1878 (Folder FF-107, Item 1878-1)
    Wood engraving: No imprint.
  - Rapid Transit of Residents., 1878 (Folder FF-107, Item 1878-no #)
    Photostat of Puck Comic.
  - The Great Walk. "Go as You Please." The Start., 1879 (Folder FF-108, Item 1879-1)
    Colored Lithograph: Signed Thomas Worth, published by Currier & Ives.